smashingapps.com 2018-06-13

# Privacy Policy | SmashingApps.com

By continuing to use the SmashingApps.com website and its online services on or after May 25, 2018, you indicate that you have read, understand and accept the terms of the SmashingApps.com Privacy Policy.

## Who we are

We are a small interest based blog for designers and developers. Our website address is: http://www.smashingapps.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

We collect information from you when you fill out a form or enter information on our site to contact us and/or provide us with feedback on our products or services Giveaway, Contest etc

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information:

  * Respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions
  * To allow us to better serve you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

**Feedburner subscription to receive updates your email etc**

We are using Google’s feedburner to generate rss feed from SmashingApps.com. If you have subscribed via email to the SmashingApps.com feeds aggregated on Google Feedburner, so you may have received email in your inbox. You can anytime unsubscribed to receive feeds from SmashingApps.com by unsubscribing from Google Feedburner for SmashingApps.com updates.

**How do we protect your information?**

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards. We only provide articles and information. We never ask for credit card numbers.

  * We use regular Malware Scanning.
  * We do not use an SSL certificate because we do not sell anything and do not ask for any confidential details from our visitors.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

If you are interested to contact us, you may use our contact form where you may have to submit your Name (Required), Email (Required), Website (user discretion) and in reply your may get a acknowledgement email on your given email address. We will not use your email address for any marketing purpose unless you requested so.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### **Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

**We have implemented the following:**

**•** Remarketing with Google AdSense

**•** Google Display Network Impression Reporting

**•** Demographics and Interests Reporting

**•** DoubleClick Platform Integration

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics, Quantcast and Hotjar services.

## Who we share your data with

We never send anyone’s data to anyone unless the visitor participated in any contest and won the reward so the vendor may contact on the given email address to provide the respective giveaway.

## How long we retain your data

In this section you should explain how long you retain personal data collected or processed by the web site. While it is your responsibility to come up with the schedule of how long you keep each dataset for and why you keep it, that information does need to be listed here. For example, you may want to say that you keep contact form entries for six months, analytics records for a year, and customer purchase records for ten years.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Website administrators can also see and edit that information. Contact form entries will also kept indefinitely for the record purpose only.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have left comments, you can that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

We are using Sucuri as a cloud-based security service for our website. It helps us to keep secure from external attacks on our website. But to realizing the fact, we can not guarantee if anything may happen unintentionally.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time either major or minor. SmashingApps.com requesting to all the the visitors to frequently check this page for any changes in our Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us via contact form.
